<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rss xmlns:atom='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/' xmlns:georss='http://www.georss.org/georss' version='2.0'><channel><atom:id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824</atom:id><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 13:40:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><title>The Hive Honeyshop: News</title><description>This page contains links to international news items featuring The Hive Honey Shop, as well as news and updates on courses, features and promotions</description><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/</link><managingEditor>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</managingEditor><generator>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>27</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-8169637552023864154</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 13:26:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2010-03-11T13:40:05.796Z</atom:updated><title>5 frame Buckfast Nuclei (live starter honeybee colony)</title><atom:summary type='text'>Nuclei: A small bee family (beekeepers call them a “Nuc”) Supplied on 5 National Frames covered with bees in a travel box.  Contains:*1 x Laying Buckfast Queen * Brood in all stages of development * Honey and pollen We are taking orders now for nucleus colonies ready from early May through to the end of June 2010. Orders are supplied on a first come first served basis. We strongly recommend you </atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2010_03_01_archive.html#8169637552023864154</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-531611366087816511</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2010 11:49:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2010-03-01T11:42:22.382Z</atom:updated><title>What happens to honeybees in the winter?</title><atom:summary type='text'>What happens to honeybees in the winter? We are asked this so many times. Our customers are concerned honeybees will not survive the cold with snow covered hives. Firstly bees no not hibernate, they stay awake throughout the winter months and venture out of their hives on warmer days. In fact snow and low temperatures are good for honeybees. They will huddle together to stay warm and are </atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2010_01_01_archive.html#531611366087816511</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-1320014751076993784</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 09:28:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2009-10-14T10:48:14.278+01:00</atom:updated><title>Bernie the Bee-Mascot for The Hive Honey Shop Arrives!</title><atom:summary type='text'>The long awaited Bernie the Bee, official mascot for The Hive Honey Shop has arrived! Three years in the making we were all looking forward to seeing 6 foot tall Bernie up close and being introduced. Bernie will travel with us to shows, conventions and lectures around the country. Bernie is currently on show for a limited time in the main window of The Hive Honey Shop. Look out for Bernie at our </atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2009_10_01_archive.html#1320014751076993784</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-8235035128738089243</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2009 12:33:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2009-10-08T14:07:38.734+01:00</atom:updated><title>Honey Bee Tea Morning at the RAC Pall Mall London</title><atom:summary type='text'>In 1995 James, head beekeeper for The Hive Honey Shop was awarded a QEST (Queen Elizabeth Scholarship Trust) Scholarship for Beekeeping &amp; Bee Disease by Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth the Queen Mother and the Royal Warrant Holders Association of Great Britain. James was invited to Clarence House to meet Her Majesty and took his family observation hive with him. It was the first time a hive </atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2009_10_01_archive.html#8235035128738089243</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-154741884324146061</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2009-08-17T19:14:30.849+01:00</atom:updated><title>Bumblebees are re-housed without harm</title><atom:summary type='text'>On Friday we were called out to rescue bees that were found flying into the gap under the top floor window of a house in London SE22. After careful inspection of the loft area we located a very large bumblebee nest hiding under the loft insulation sheets. They had been there for some time and were using the insulation felt as their nesting material. The home owner is having that area refurbished.</atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2009_08_01_archive.html#154741884324146061</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-995093131431475723</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2009 21:05:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2009-08-16T22:39:50.945+01:00</atom:updated><title>Great Day at Covent Garden- Good Food Market</title><atom:summary type='text'>The Hive had a great day out meeting the public and spreading the word of Beekeeping! We had our 4th generation beekeepers on hand chatting to the children about the benefits that bees do for our planet. They helped the children roll their own free beeswax candles that were very well received in deed. Thank you to Covent Garden for inviting us.</atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2009_08_01_archive.html#995093131431475723</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-3000563869891361827</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 18:58:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2009-08-10T20:42:28.362+01:00</atom:updated><title>Hear us on BBC London Radio 94.9 LIVE!</title><atom:summary type='text'>The Hive Honey Shop will be interviewed live on BBC London Radio with Robert Elms. So tune in on Tuesday August 11th from 1:40-2:00pm. Robert Elms presents London's best magazine show with eclectic music &amp; great guests.</atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2009_08_01_archive.html#3000563869891361827</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-2627316571993506562</guid><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2009 17:48:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2009-08-08T19:39:48.807+01:00</atom:updated><title>Speakers Corner Event-Covent Garden Real Food Market</title><atom:summary type='text'>The Hive Honey Shop have been invited to Covent Garden to be featured as the local honey and bee expert who will talk about bee keeping, the benefits of using locally sourced honey, medicinal purposes and interesting facts on urban beekeeping. We will be in the Covent Garden Piazza on Thursday August 13th from 1-1:30pm. We are providing a FREE beeswax candle rolling session for children. So they </atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2009_08_01_archive.html#2627316571993506562</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-3224021343156791566</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 09:57:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2009-06-16T11:40:40.976+01:00</atom:updated><title>Bumblebee Rescue Service</title><atom:summary type='text'>Did you know that The Hive Honey Shop run a Bumblebee Rescue Service throughout the southwest! Its true. We have 20 years experience of carefully handling the difficult removal of bees from just about any area of a property. We have been inundated with calls to remove bumblebees from weird and wonderful places. So far this year alone has seen us carefully removing bees from compost bins, inner </atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2009_06_01_archive.html#3224021343156791566</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-7332760148479741606</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2009 20:53:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2009-05-17T22:11:25.501+01:00</atom:updated><title>Urban Wandsworth Honey &amp; Pollen</title><atom:summary type='text'>Now in the making Urban Wandsworth Honey &amp; Fresh Raw Pollen! Fingers crossed that the weather forecasters predictions for a long hot summer come true. If this is the case we should be able to provide an abundance of London honey. Pictured above is just one of our many city locations.</atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2009_05_01_archive.html#7332760148479741606</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-1941551706877876401</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 19:56:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2009-05-13T17:41:57.507+01:00</atom:updated><title>Honey - the sweetest cure for hayfever</title><atom:summary type='text'>As the pollen count rises, try honey as a natural weapon against hayfever. This is what the Telegraph said in a feature on how using local unpasteurised honey can help with hayfever.Have a read: http://www.telegraph.co.uk/health/5135837/Honey-the-sweetest-cure-for-hayfever.html They listed The Hive Honey Shop's HayfeGUARD, local honey and pollen as one of the Top Five Healing Honeys. Launched </atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2009_05_01_archive.html#1941551706877876401</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-5517702492717545125</guid><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2008 00:48:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2008-10-17T02:04:18.214+01:00</atom:updated><title>Apple Harvest Day at our Bee Heaven Farm, Surrey</title><atom:summary type='text'>It was a busy and successful apple picking day on the farm in preparation for juicing. Friends and family all joined in to lend a hand or hands! All in all we hand picked over three tons of apples! The really amazing thing is, the orchard has over 200 trees with 76 different varieties.When we press the apples, on average there are more than 55 different varieties of apples in each bottle of our </atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2008_10_01_archive.html#5517702492717545125</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-5973911934351766473</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 23:19:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2008-10-17T02:10:48.193+01:00</atom:updated><title>Beekeeping Talk a Success!</title><atom:summary type='text'>           The beekeeping talk at Waterstones, Clapham was a true success. 75 tickets were sold for this event and there was only standing room left for those arriving later. The evening lecture covered many of the problems facing bees and beekeeping at present throughout the world today.James, The Hive Honey Shops head beekeeper, was asked by Waterstones Books SW11 to speak at this years </atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2008_10_01_archive.html#5973911934351766473</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-4799346261174872772</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2008 17:27:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2008-09-06T18:46:14.231+01:00</atom:updated><title>Cowes, Isle of Wight- Beehive on Building</title><atom:summary type='text'>         I was visiting beekeepers on the Isle of Wight. While in Cowes I noticed a fantastic 3D skep beehive wall plaque. It is quite large and in perfect condition. I went inside the shop, now selling yacht and nautical goods. The staff had no idea why it was there or the history behind the building.So my question is. Does anyone recognise it? Can anyone tell me more about it. There is a free </atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2008_09_01_archive.html#4799346261174872772</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-4904232718918893901</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2008 21:27:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2008-08-29T23:47:55.439+01:00</atom:updated><title>Come &amp; Meet us LIVE at Waterstone's Clapham!</title><atom:summary type='text'>Welcome to the 2008 SW11 Literary Festival organised by Waterstone's Books &amp; the Clapham Junction Town Centre Partnership. The Hive Honey Shop has been invited to take part in this prestigious annual literary event.This festival gives book lovers the opportunity to meet some of their favourite writers and to discover new ones, to attend workshops to sharpen their writing talent or to try their </atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2008_08_01_archive.html#4904232718918893901</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-1800834266362031322</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2008 14:05:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2008-10-17T02:07:34.219+01:00</atom:updated><title>Honey Shop- acknowledged by Food Experts</title><atom:summary type='text'>Henrietta Green, British local &amp; regional food expert has won several awards including a Guild of Food Writers Award for the greatest contribution to British food among others.In her search for the BEST- whether a place to buy, eat or learn, Henrietta has criss-crossed Britain several times in her quest. The results were first published in her award-winning British Food Finds in 1987, during 1993</atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2008_08_01_archive.html#1800834266362031322</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-2624719433957990609</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 16:56:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2008-08-12T20:22:55.014+01:00</atom:updated><title>LIVE Interview with BBC Radio London 94.9FM</title><atom:summary type='text'>        The Hive Honey Shop was asked to take part in a live radio interview at the shop on August 11th. Stevan Bennett from BBC Radio London was the interviewer and asked James, our head Beekeeper and co-owner to step up to the mic and describe what its like being a professional beekeeper.The interview lasted 30 mins and guest speakers included Simon Kilks, a spokesperson and member of the </atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2008_08_01_archive.html#2624719433957990609</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-5942498141120444128</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 23:12:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2008-08-07T10:30:24.212+01:00</atom:updated><title>BBC Newsnight interview The Honey Shop</title><atom:summary type='text'>BBCs Newsnight contacted The Hive as they are currently working on a film involving the decline of the honeybee in the UK and around the world, and the level of research and funding that is going towards it.The crew arrived and filmed at the shop asking questions about how we collect our honey and how the decline in bee populations will impact on pollination, global finance and the honey industry</atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2008_08_01_archive.html#5942498141120444128</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-8619468153683329447</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 23:07:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2008-08-27T17:52:27.736+01:00</atom:updated><title>CCD interview with The Hive Honey Shop, London</title><atom:summary type='text'>Bloomberg TV news today interviewed our head beekeeper about the plight of the honey bee in England. CCD ( colony collapse disorder) is a hot issue in the press at the moment and journalists want to find out more and what the present situation is.Bloomberg TV televise financial news both in the US and the UK. The obvious impact on the US financial market,  due to the decline of honey bees and </atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2008_08_01_archive.html#8619468153683329447</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-904430079303341307</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2008 00:27:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2008-08-01T02:00:29.500+01:00</atom:updated><title>HayfeGUARD now available in Wimbledom</title><atom:summary type='text'>Do you suffer from hay fever and live near Wimbledon? Then you are saved! ABC Pharmacy in ELYS Department Store, Wimbledon now stock our natural hay fever remedy, 'HayfeGUARD'. They have branches throughout the SW of London. To find your nearest stockist have a look at their website: see  www.abcpharmacy.co.uk                                 Email: abcpharmacy.ely@npanet.co.ukFor more information</atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2008_08_01_archive.html#904430079303341307</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-9117501345992934281</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 12:18:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2008-07-30T13:20:24.010+01:00</atom:updated><title>Beekeeping with The Hive</title><atom:summary type='text'>We are very proud to announce our new practical beekeeping blog called "Beekeeping with The Hive". This will be a diary of our daily beekeeping activities full of pictures and tips which we hope you will find useful and interesting.See Beekeeping with The Hive here</atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2008_07_01_archive.html#9117501345992934281</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-6903490408314284562</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 18:10:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2008-07-30T17:52:46.106+01:00</atom:updated><title>BBC Olive Magazine, Food Heroes</title><atom:summary type='text'>BBC Olive Magazine -March 2008 IssueExpert Advise *Food Heroes*WHY YOU SHOULD BUY ....The Hive's HoneyWhen it comes to top quality honey, British bees do it best. words by David McCandless</atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2008_02_01_archive.html#6903490408314284562</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-111126163700283308</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2005 19:07:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2008-02-17T19:45:24.958Z</atom:updated><title>FHM, For Him magazine Special Promotion with The Hive</title><atom:summary type='text'>FHM Magazine has enlisted the help of The Hive Honey Shop to help promote their new March cover girl. The competition, known as 'Finding the 2005 High Street Honey', gave way to FHM contacting The Hive, asking them to bottle special limited edition honey featuring a photo of Natalie, the winner, in her bra. 'It has never been done before' said the managing director, but The Hive agreed and now </atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2005_03_01_archive.html#111126163700283308</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-111003567601109200</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2003 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2005-03-19T19:05:19.850Z</atom:updated><title>Treats from the Edwardian Country House</title><atom:summary type='text'>Channel 4: 23rd May 2003James and Hugh the presenter discuss how the Edwardians kept honeybees and how they used the by-products they harvested from their bees. Shot on location at James's orchard/apiary, 'Bee Heaven Farm' in Surrey surrounded by 180 rare apple trees and 40 beehives on site. Don't miss it!Visit the website at Channel 4: The Edwardian Country House </atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2003_05_01_archive.html#111003567601109200</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item><item><guid isPermaLink='false'>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-11230824.post-111003640035688720</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 14:25:00 +0000</pubDate><atom:updated>2005-03-05T15:26:40.360Z</atom:updated><title>A Hive Of Activity</title><atom:summary type='text'>from Country Homes &amp; Interiors May 2002As May arrives, bees that have been still since the autumn prepare for the season ahead, stirred by the new spring blossoms and pollens that fill the air with their heady, seductive perfumesUrban settings such as Clapham, in south-east London, seem an unlikely place to find bees busily working away, gathering nectar from the smart window boxes and tidy </atom:summary><link>http://www.thehivehoneyshop.co.uk/news/2002_05_01_archive.html#111003640035688720</link><author>noreply@blogger.com (The Hive Honey Shop)</author></item></channel></rss>